# LUKKHANA TIPCHAINAK Software Tester/QA

Nakhon Ratchasima, Thailand Mobile: (+66) 91 469 9338 | Email: lukkhanatl@gmail.com github.com/oilly18 | linkedin.com/in/lukkhanatl/

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

With over 12 years as a Credit Analyst, I bring strong analytical thinking, problem-solving, and attention to detail skills from the banking and finance sectors. Recently, I've developed proficiency in the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) and software testing/QA. Known for my strong communication and collaboration skills, I am eager to leverage my industry expertise, technical skills, and software testing knowledge to enhance software quality and performance in the tech sector.

### **SKILLS**

Technical skills: HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, SQL, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Git/GitHub, Figma, Trello, Postman, Software Testing (manual)

Behavioral skills: Growth Mindset, Teamwork, Time Management, Personal Responsibility, Attention to detail, Problem-Solving, Communication

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Junior Software Developer (Bootcamp) (Apr 2024 - Jul 2024) Generation Thailand

- Developed an E-commerce web Application Project following the scrum methodology, divided into front-end using HTML, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, React with React-router and Axios as the main dependency. In the back-end, it uses Node.js and Express to manage the RESTful API and uses MongoDB as a database.
- Developed soft skills such as time management, personal responsibility, attention to detail, problem-solving, growth mindset, communication, persistence, and teamwork.

### Credit Analyst (Jan 2012 - Jan 2024)

### The Government Savings Bank

- Conducted credit assessments on housing loan and SMEs loan applicants, evaluating financial statements and business plans.
- Analyzed borrower cash flows, profitability, and industry trends to assess repayment capacity, achieving an approval rate of 80%.
- Collaborated closely with the loan officer team to structure loan terms and conditions, ensuring alignment with risk appetite.
- Managed portfolios for 300+ housing loans and 30+ SMEs loans, monitoring repayment performance and conducting reviews.

# Branch Officer (Mar 2009 - Mar 2011)

### Kasikornbank

- Managed daily cash of 100+ transactions, including deposits, withdrawals, and currency exchange for customers.
- Verified the accuracy of 100+ transactions daily and maintained detailed records to reconcile discrepancies.
- Built and maintained strong relationships with customers, fostering trust and loyalty.

### **Au Pair** (Aug 2006 - Sep 2007)

### American Institute For Foreign Study(AIFS), Maryland, U.S.A.

- Provided attentive and nurturing care to children, ensuring their safety, well-being, and development.
- Facilitated cultural exchange by sharing cultural traditions and practices with children and participating in host family activities.

### **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATE**

# **Bachelor Degree in Business Computer** (Mar 2003)

Vongchavalitkul University, Nakhon Ratchasima 2nd Class Honors.

## Foundations of Software Testing: Manual Testing (May 2024 -Jul 2024)

FutureSkill, Online Certificate

- Enter the world of technology by becoming a QA.
- Basic knowledge for QA and tester.
- Manual testing and various tools for managing tests.
- Workshop on API and Functional Manual Testing.
- Test plan planning techniques, creating test cases and reporting results with a test report.